technology is risky when somebody has an
idea for a new app they have to put in
so much guesswork as to what the user
wants and needs then they make an
iteration that they hope meets most of
the needs of the people that they've
made it for the product itself could be
faulty it could be a crappy product in
which case the markets doing its job by
not letting you stay on the market but
most of the time with technology it's
90% of the way there to be usable but
it's broken in a tiny way that breaks
the whole thing it meets the needs or
fixes the problem for 90% it fixes the
problem 90% for some of the people but
that 10% isn't getting you all the way
there and so you're not getting the
people on board and the issue is even if
you have a perfect product even if the
product you create is absolutely amazing
you have no guarantee that people are
gonna find it your marketing strategy
might be off you might not be going to
the right people you might have a very
niche community that you've created for
that is life-changing for that niche but
how do you how do you get it to them the
funding model can often be off where the
funding model itself breaks the mission
or you can't make enough money to stay
afloat because you you might need the
needs of the people but they're not
willing to put it to pay the price
you've set it at because that's the
price you need to stay afloat it's not
necessarily supply meeting demand it's
not meeting your people where they're at
it's just setting the price is what we
need to be able to break even because we
don't have a market and so the funny one
woke me off also trust and security with
every new app that comes on the market
and then goes under in its first year
which is 9 out of 10 of them it hurts
the next ones that come on board that
doesn't really happen in the non
technology space if there's a new retail
store or a new coffee shop on my block
and I buy something from it I might be
upset that they go out of business
because I liked their product but it's
not going to make me not buy clothes in
the future or not buy a coffee in the
future because I have the thing it does
hurt me that it went out of business
right I can't get my favorite cup of
coffee but I still had those cups of
coffee it if putting your information on
a app it's only gonna happen if I have
trust that you're gonna be around in two
three ten years then it hurts you to not
have security and Trust in it to not
have it be transparent that I can see
why I can trust you who are you how I
should I trust you
those are two different options two
different problems trust in you as a
person in you as a company but also just
faith that you're gonna be around for
for any amount of time one of the other
big issues that is risky is the market
itself is saturated so unless you come
up with a truly innovative product
you're all competing for the same people
and there's very little that can
differentiate you in the marketplace
with an app very little that's
proprietary and so all of the data and
all of the people are spread out and how
you win a technology is generally being
bought up by one of the big four because
they have the people they have the money
and they're not spread out so besides
between the four of them and so when
we're competing with them it's very
risky to create technology and the more
that come in and fail and there aren't
systems in place to improve them if
they're 90% of the way there
and there isn't that extra way to get
that 10% from the users to say well I'd
use it if right if this wasn't ten
dollars a month and it was five dollars
a month or it was based on ads I'd use
it then that there isn't a way to
improve it together there isn't way to
trust it together and every new person
that comes on the market every new app
has to start back at square one not
knowing why all the ones who were in
that marketplace before failed so tech
is risky I am creating a video series
that explains why a technology
cooperative is most of the good and
basically none of the bad and why we
need a technology cooperative to create
a better world
a better world is on its way please like
and subscribe